短期旅行就像打开了疯狂的大门
To mini break is to prize open the crack of crazy,
你会有离开家的荒谬想法
behind which lurks the absurd notion of leaving your house,
某种运动病
certain motion sickness
以及接触其他文化的可怕前景
and the terrifying prospect of interacting with other cultures.
How can a cat get his or her bearings,
字幕
without jettersing a full bag of marbles,
不要因此而生气 因为我
but do not uncoil your private fury for I a name same twig
字幕
called Richard Ayoade am here
把你短暂拖沓的假期变得紧凑
to get your short haul holiday game tight.
我曾和一些名人
I once yoked to some people who have long
一起出游
since lost their right to earthly anonymity,
我将带你飞奔过一场最棒的短假期
am going to take you hurtling through a maxi mini-break.
这场旅行将极其残酷
This is travel without mercy.
今夜 四十八小时在一座相比之下
Tonight, 48 hours in the city that
使约克郡黯淡无光的城市 纽约
in some way has eclipsed York, New York.
去年有五千八百万游客来到这里
58 million tourists came here last year
in dizzy plunderers sites, skyscrapers,
字幕
and most every type of shizz this convention commands.
Joining me for the full furlong in this dense fruit
字幕
is Canadian comedian Katherine Ryan.
Together we will extract edification a museums of diverse sizes.
字幕
Do you want me to enter another reference number?
No, I don’t
字幕
And Bolster our blood sugar
I think there is more sugar than bread in
字幕
so I place it in the Harribo family.
We are here, but should we have come?
字幕
An 8 hour flight followed by a 40 minute taxi ride
reveals New York to be on the outer rim of short haul-erie.
字幕
We just had a long flight but I feel no jet lag.
I feel terrible.
字幕
I find it very difficult to cope with any form of travel, I’m weak.
Yet, you’re a travel man?
字幕
Its unfortunate casting, you’re probably wondering why the heck
I have brought you to these climbs.
字幕
Are you wondering that?
I wasn’t going to ask you that until after the bridge,
字幕
but, Richard why have you brought me to Manhattan?
Well, that question is timely.
字幕
New York or the Giant Apple has the population of 8 and a half mill.
Makes is America’s largest city housing twice as many torsos,
字幕
as the frankly quaint LA.
It’s the birth place of the teddy bear,
字幕
hip hop and my desert island must have, toilet paper.
It contains 10 national parks,
字幕
247 museums and art galleries
as well as in a safety deposit box Albert Einstein’s eye balls
字幕
and Jay Z recently gave me his personal assurance that
the streets here are so good that they will both inspire you
字幕
and make you feel brand new alongside some other statements
that were basically just boasting.
字幕
New York has 5 boroughs,
all with varying degrees of interest and attraction.
字幕
But for a clock-conscious ram raid of the city’s top
tat we bunker in Manhattan.
字幕
And specifically, the high line hotel in the chic Chelsea district.
Thank you very much
字幕
Thank you
Wow, that bag is visible
字幕
Thank you, have a good day
You can see it at the baggage claim
字幕
You can see that from space,
I imagine there is going to be outfit changes
字幕
Many
Really
字幕
A must
Blimey
字幕
The high line had free to use bicycles and a coffee van.
The rooms feature vintage furniture phones and typewriters.
字幕
You know like the ones you use at home.
Hello
字幕
Katherine what’s going on?
Oh hey boss, I’m just composing a short novel
字幕
Ok, you need to stop that, we’ve to go
-I’ll see you downstairs, bye, bye, bye  -Ok, bye
字幕
After a gruelling 2 minute wait
we hit the subway underground aficionados will already know it
字幕
as the seventh most used underground on earth
with 1 point 763 billion journeys a year.
字幕
You’ve probably got a ranking system of your favourite
underground transport networks, how does this rank?
字幕
New York City subway ranks higher than Germany
Really
字幕
Definitely higher than Toronto
But, um not as good as London
字幕
Thank you
We’re rollicking uptown to midtown
字幕
to curve our corneas round the cities sites.
Well here we are,
字幕
about to enjoy Elm Green and  Dragset’s Van Gough’s ear,
This thankfully temporary art work guards the 5th avenue
字幕
end of the Rockefeller centre, home to radio city music hall,
TV studios and all heap of other biz.
字幕
It is exquisite
Ah, it’s a triumph to the art deco style
字幕
A trip to the top of 30 rock allows a bod a full oculus swoop of the city skyline.
Richard
字幕
Wow,
ok, well you know yes this is densely clustered
字幕
It is
Prince Charles would hate this
字幕
Let’s put this via a screen, so that we can really drink this in.
This is going to tell us what we are looking at
字幕
What are we looking at?
We are looking at the empire state building
字幕
That’s cool
You can go round, Chrysler building
字幕
Oh yeah, I like that one
-Do you like it? That’s a good one  -It’s one of my fave’s
字幕
Do you know you can buy air space
around your building preventing anyone else
字幕
from building there and obstructing your views.
I did not know that
字幕
Sensing myself out of my conversational depth,
I suggest we leave and do something else.
字幕
The hot dog is a New York obsession.
Last year 2 point 5 bill dollars of sausage was sunk in the city.
字幕
Papaya King are the dukes of the dog scene,
with 84 years on the clock.
字幕
It’s good, yeah.
I actually wrote my University thesis on the hot dog
字幕
and have many pertinent things to say about its cultural,
historical and socio-political impact.
字幕
But, just as I was about to speak Katherine railroaded me.
I think it’s important that we had a hot dog in New York.
字幕
It’s the type of food that you don’t feel super proud about eating
but it was kind of naughty and fun.
字幕
Let’s bust, you go.
Thank you so much Richard
字幕
Fine
Thank you
字幕
Having used uncharacteristic politeness
to hide my fury we hoff up to the largest
字幕
and most visited museum in all of America.
It’s the Met.
字幕
Wow
Within the context of Manhattan
字幕
it kind of looks boutique like a bungalow,
they haven’t used the air space wisely
字幕
at all considering the value of the Real Estate.
The problem we face, 2 million exhibits, our time is limited.
字幕
What are we going to do?
I’ll tell you what we are going to do, off camera
字幕
Wait for me
In an effort to condense this mammoth museum,
字幕
I’ve secured the services of an independent guide,
who insists he will make our visit,
字幕
subversive, interactive, fun and fast.
We are going to fly through this museum.
字幕
Ok, good we are going to blast it into our retina and move on.
I love it
字幕
Ok
Well if we are going to do this,
字幕
we have got to get this thing started, shall we.
Yes, let’s get it started
字幕
We have a little museum hack tradition that gets us going
because I know you want to move fast
字幕
Yes, I do
All hands in the centre please,
字幕
we go down on mu and up on seum
and then charge into the met
字幕
This is quite a hack
I’m nearly 40
字幕
You’re nearly 40
OK
字幕
OK, well you’re going to have to keep up
Squash it down, move on
字幕
Museum
Alright, let’s go
字幕
That must endear you to people
And so begins our slide across the surface of the Met’s 17 acres of galleries.
字幕
Arms and armour
I like that they give a little protection to the horses as well.
字幕
This is Henry the eighth
And this is?
字幕
Before
Ok
字幕
And after
So as he aged he became less concerned about his groin
字幕
Like many men, let’s move on
Welcome to Washington crossing the Delaware
字幕
Woah
And is this for Sale? It’s not for sale
字幕
Next pre historic and early Greek art.
What have we got?
字幕
We got this, alright
Ok
字幕
Check this out they think this may be a 6000 year old selfie
Commentators claim that the proportions of the sculpture
字幕
mean the artist may have been looking at herself without a mirror.
Ooh yes you are looking at this from the wrong angle Gentlemen.
字幕
I know
And I like that she has natural breasts
字幕
Yes
Is this for sale?
字幕
No, unfortunately not
Ok, let’s move on
字幕
Welcome to the temple of Dendur
Thank you this is, I mean it’s extraordinary
字幕
The positioning of this gift from Egypt
was decided by former first lady Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis.
字幕
Jackie O had purchased a brand new penthouse apartment
right across the street from the museum,
字幕
this is lit up 24/7 365 and suddenly the tabloids start
referring to this as Jackie’s night light.
字幕
It’s excellent
-It’s beautiful isn’t it?  -It’s really good
字幕
You don’t have to travel to Egypt,
that’s what I like about museums
字幕
Oh yeah, you can go all over the world in one afternoon
Oh, great
字幕
Our frantic twirl takes us to the roof
where on we behold one of the museums newest exhibits
字幕
This is by Cornelia Parker, called psychobarn
Yeah
字幕
Yep
Right, thank you for having us, it’s an excellent museum
字幕
Oh well that’s wonderful to hear
I think now that I have added my approbations,
字幕
watch those till receipts sore, my influence is huge
I didn’t even know what a museum was until I met Richard
字幕
Exactly
I bow to you my friend
字幕
You mustn’t
Alright
字幕
You’ll start a trend, thank you
Bye guys
字幕
You’ve just gone now, you’re out of my life
I’m just out, we are never talking again
字幕
That’s so weird isn’t it
As evening encroaches in this series of moving images
字幕
we wend our way back to Chelsea
where we towel down and prepare for times to come.
字幕
Hi, this is good, Chris De Burgh would love it, let’s go
Hi
字幕
We are taking a sunset stroll along the high line
from which our hotel snatched it’s Monika
字幕
Straight down
OK
字幕
It’s a former elevated railway, now linear park.
Greenfingered viewers will know this
字幕
as the work of the uber influential garden designer, Piet Oudolf,
whose prairie plantings looks particularly plaintive in the setting sun.
字幕
Thoughts on this
Its glorious
字幕
Let’s move on
In a most second of parts we will shower in zucheros
字幕
Wow that’s so sugary it’s almost spicy
Embark on a pro-long skid
字幕
This is a kind of very slow moving zombie apocalypse
And start sweating in a jumped up garage
字幕
This is hell in here, why am I here?
We are more than half way through a two day dalliant in NYC,
字幕
part one featured the following sub headings,
taxi, hotel, Rockefeller, hot dog, museum, high line sing along.
字幕
You’re going to have to keep up
Ok
字幕
Day two begins with a frankly fascist 7. 30 am start.
Are we going for breakfast?
字幕
-Yes, we are going for a cronut  -A cronut
In May 2013, after 6 months toil chef Dominique Ansel launched,
字幕
a paradigm shifting piece of patisserie he called it the cronut.
A croissant dough is fried, then coated in sugar,
字幕
injected with cream and glazed.
Such is the demand for this confection
字幕
that queues form at 7am in the morning.
What time do they open, 8?
字幕
Yep
And then it all kicks off
字幕
I’m so tired and a strict two cronuts per person limit is in forced.
We’ll get 4 cronuts
字幕
Four
We’ll get our maximum allotted amount of cronuts
字幕
Sure, no problem
One food writer claimed a cronut contains 1300 calories;
字幕
over half a man’s recommended daily allowance.
The bakery says this incorrect and open quote absurd, closed quote.
字幕
Controversy like this is part of what makes a pastry seem so freaking exciting.
I’m getting leakage
字幕
Yeah me too
There is stuff inside here I did not expect
字幕
Wow, I think I have just developed diabetes
I think there is more sugar than bread
字幕
so I’ve placed it in the, in the Harribo family.
Right
字幕
I really like all the wetness of it, all the cream and sauce
I can eat this, then I could lie down
字幕
Let my blood adjust,
while these tiny diabetic birds flap around me
字幕
and find bits of sugar from the corner of my mouth
This is great
字幕
This is the most sugar you have ever had in your life
I know, yeah
字幕
You’ve lost control of your entire waist,
wow mines so sugary it’s almost spicy.
字幕
I don’t even know what happened there.
That was really intense,
字幕
it’s a very emotional experience eating this as well,
you’re up you’re down, I don't know if I hate myself now,
字幕
or whether I’m pleased, I kind of won something,
I’m in an elite club,
字幕
but essentially I’m just scarfing sugar,
what’s happening?
字幕
You need a second cronut to get you out of the first cronut hole
I’m slightly upset
字幕
Bang that’s a napkin drop
You’ve eaten all the cronut
字幕
Yes, how do you feel, I’ve got a headache, how do you feel?
I feel absolutely euphoric
字幕
I’m going to put this back up
Ok
字幕
My hands are shaking, ok let’s go
, let’s walk this, I need a second, I’m dipping, I’m dipping.
字幕
Before we are engulfed by insulin we flounce off to the ferry terminal
and board the Manhattan mainstay.
字幕
It makes me feel like live stock
In a good way
字幕
There’s not in a good way
The Staten Island ferry runs 24 hours a day 7 days a week.
字幕
And it’s 100% gratis offering travellers a time and cost effective
if some-what distant look of an NYC landmark.
字幕
And there she is
It’s an it, it’s not a person, it’s a statue, it’s an it,
字幕
I’m never sure about that hat,
it seems quite un-welcoming, quite pointing.
字幕
I see it as a friendly nod to nearby birds who might want to have a rest
Right
字幕
Do you feel like you have seen the statue of liberty now Richard?
I actually have seen it, so it’s more than a feeling, it’s a reality
字幕
With the temperature firing into the one hundreds
we courier into central park.
字幕
Visitors can explore this uptown rectangle by carriage, bike or leg.
After a brief off camera consultation with our separate stylists
字幕
we decide to get into our sports shizz
What could be better than learning to rollerblade in this heat?
字幕
Roller Joel’s created the first ever inline skating school
in New York City in 1988.
字幕
Former clients include Cindy Crawford who used to work as a model.
Hey Guys
字幕
Hi, are you roller Joel?
I am indeed roller Joel and you are?
字幕
Richard
Richard, a pleasure to meet you
字幕
Katherine
Katherine, so welcome to New York,
字幕
welcome to Central Park, so have you skated before?
No
字幕
Have you skated before?
I have a little bit as a child
字幕
I will make you expert skaters when I’m done with you
Ok, really?
字幕
Natural pessimist Joel gets us padded up
This is going to be a good sequence when it’s cut together.
字幕
Before we bring the thunder
You know this could be the official Travel Man super hero uniform
字幕
I think you over estimate how much merchandise we push out
I’m just going to pull you, you’re a natural, look at you.
字幕
I feel like a retired dalek
Now put your hands forward on your knees and roll
字幕
This is a deleted scene from night of the living dead
Katherine choose herself to be a classic ringer
字幕
That’s it
Where as I develop instant osteoporosis
字幕
Now when you come back next time,
Sure, I’ll come on foot
字幕
we are going to cover a much extensive tour
We can cover all the acres on skates
字幕
But we do manage a credible creep round the park,
taking in the Bandshell used as a location in the film Breakfast at Tiffany’s
字幕
Hands forward, no, no, no, no
and the Bethesda terrace,
字幕
which you will recognise from Stuart Little 2
Wow, this is not my natural habitat
字幕
We finish at the Cherry Hill fountain
which many mistakenly think is the fountain at the start of Friends
字幕
Well thank goodness that was now something, I appreciate it
Well something is better than nothing
字幕
Good luck
I hope you had a good time, now don’t forget keep on rolling
字幕
Keep on joeling
Oh, I like that even better
字幕
That’s good
Knowing that mo can never be out-bond we swiftly Segway
字幕
from one sequence to another to create the illusion of momentum.
Look at this
字幕
It is quite grand
It is
字幕
Grand central terminus
Terminus?
字幕
Not station
Why not?
字幕
No trains pass through here,
it’s the end of the line and the beginning of the line,
字幕
750 thousand people pass through here daily.
It used so much granite that there is still radiation here,
字幕
we are in the middle of a radiation zone,
And they just decided that’s fine
字幕
There is nothing they can do about it,
there is that much granite, let’s hit the dining concourse
字幕
Yes
This corner of the station is home an acoustic anomaly
字幕
Hello
Hi Richard, how are you?
字幕
I feel slightly unnerved by this
Sound is reflected by the curve of the ceiling
字幕
so we can hear each other clearly despite standing ten metres
apart facing opposite directions.
字幕
This is a much easier for me to communicate that normal
It’s a lot easier
字幕
There is none of that strange eye contact business
or you know engaging with some ones face.
字幕
You know it just looks like you’re having a wee
It does, I’m going to step away now
字幕
Ok
My urine still warming the wall we canter to China town
字幕
for one last carafe for culture.
A museum that stands in rude opposition to the Met’s epic sweep.
字幕
Hello
Hello welcome to the museum
字幕
That curb is dangerous by the way, I almost killed myself.
So, the double m is silent.
字幕
Yes
The first M but the second M you sound
字幕
If you want to
Say it again slowly
字幕
Mmuseumm
Ok
字幕
Mmuseumm
Ok, Mmuseumm, thank you
字幕
Opened in 2012 the Mmuseumm is housed in a goods elevator,
which this afternoon has reached the temperature of fresh lava.
字幕
My glasses are slipping off my nose.
When they say the museum challenges you to find meaning
字幕
and objects from around the world which will be overlooked,
dismissed or ignored and they actually say this in this condescending sign
字幕
they’re not joking about it being a challenge.
Exhibits include different kinds of cornflakes,
字幕
and things left by illegal immigrants crossing in to America.
These are good these Trump accessories, energy drink
字幕
He has an energy drink
I actually own the Art of the Comeback myself but in paperback
字幕
How is it?
It’s heavy going
字幕
OK
It’s heavy going
字幕
Maybe he wrote it on the energy drink
Yeah
字幕
Above the Trump collection are cookies displaying major events of 2015
including the VW emission scandal and edible instances of the refuge crisis.
字幕
There is also an audio guide,
god help us to unlock the complex imagery.
字幕
Would you like to listen to the audio recording
I’d like my head to cool down
字幕
It’s very hot
I tell you what the story of this,
字幕
this incredible melting man,
that’s what the story is right here.
字幕
I’m not even incredible,
it’s like the slightly bemused melting man
字幕
I want you to be comfortable, that’s why I am here.
That’s what friendship is
字幕
This is hell, this is hell in here,
I’m in a lift on my phone looking at weird I mean, this is hell.
字幕
Do you want me to enter another reference number?
No I don’t
字幕
I’m very hot, I’m sorry, I apologise.
It’s not your fault, you didn’t design this
字幕
She didn’t
You were just out of work, well thank you,
字幕
I’m going to leave, this has been something, it really has.
So great, thank you so much
字幕
-Thank you  -Thank you for coming to the Mmuseaumm
We had a really great time
字幕
My personal eye index at in candescent,
I insist we blast free of Manhattan
字幕
and across it’s eponymous bridge to Brooklyn,
leaving Katherine just seconds to source a new outfit.
字幕
Thank you for letting me change my shoes
Your more than welcome
字幕
I keep causing you delays but I’m so comfortable now
250 thousand people cross the bridge daily, 120,000 vehicles
字幕
It’s a good bridge
One hell of a bridge, 1825 metres
字幕
It feels like longer
But enough of this bridge based baloney;
字幕
the final reckoning is upon us.
Let’s sum this up
字幕
while we are upstaged by the background, how’s the trip?
I’m absolutely thrilled that
字幕
you have brought me to New York Richard.
-Sure  -I had a fab time
字幕
-Well you’re very welcome  -I loved the Rockerfeller centre, I loved the Met.
Yes
字幕
Mmuseumm
Yes
字幕
I even loved the food tourism
For me, this trip was of two halves,
字幕
before cronuts and after cronuts,
after cronuts was a blurr,
字幕
I don’t know what’s happened, I don’t know what’s going on now,
it’s still going through my blood.
字幕
Our trip to New York cost £975 per person
small beans for a weekend cramped with culture comradery and cronuts
字幕
new York is very good
city of dreams
字幕
it think they certainly fill themselves a city on a national scale
if not an international scale
字幕
it has been my absolute pleasure to join you
I am thrilled to be here
字幕
you are more than welcome,
we will settle up at the airport
字幕
okay
this wasn’t cheap
字幕
No of course not